(コテツ)よっしゃ 任務終わり！
All right, our shift's over.
Time to close the gate.
(イズモ)閉門 閉門っと…。
この時間からの外出届は
出ていなかったはずだが…。
We didn't get any advance notices
about departures at this hour...
おい 閉門時間だぞ。
Hey, we're closing the gate!
待て…。
Wait!
"sekkaku hareta kara" tte iiwake o hitotsu houri nage
"The sun's finally out", I shout out an excuse
gareeji kara ikioi makase tobidashita
and fly out of the garage eagerly
mokutekichi wa minami e
I head south, pedaling hard toward the ocean
fumikonde iku pedaru wa umi no hou
chizu nante minai kimerareta you na ruuto wa iya
I don't want to take a route that
I already know without looking at a map
dareka no wadachi wa ashi ga torarete komaru
Following someone else's well-worn path
will only slow me down
isshinfuran ni egaku icchokusen rain wa
The straight line drawn with my heart and soul
boku ni shika mirenai panorama e tsuzuku
continues on toward a panorama that only I can see
konma ni-byou no mirai e ima o kirihiraite ike!
Unlock the present into a 0.2 second future!
tonikaku koge
Pedal until the end
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
Leaving the Village
(カカシ)サスケ。
(カカシ)こんな夜に
こんなことしてまで→
Where are you going
at this hour?
いったい
どこへ行こうっていうのかな？
And why would you need
to resort to all this?
(サスケ)アンタには感謝している。
I'm grateful to you...
だが まだ足りないんだ。
but this isn't enough.
こんな生ぬるいところでは
それは得られない。
I'm not satisfied with the lackluster level
that I'm at right now.
うん？
俺は 力を手に入れる。
I'm going to get power...
もうひとりの三忍のもとで。
at the side of that
other Sannin.
まさか お前…。
Don't tell me you're—?!
しまった！
Damn it!
もう遅い。
It's too late.
サスケ…。
Sasuke!
(綱手)うちはの幻術は きつい。
しばらくは動けんぞ。
The Uchiha's genjutsu
is powerful.
You won't be able to do
anything for a while.
(ミナト)大丈夫かい？ カカシ。
Are you all right, Kakashi?
ええ それより サスケが…。
Yes, never mind me. Sasuke's...
(ヒルゼン)先ほど
イズモとコテツから聞いた。
I heard earlier from
Izumo and Kotetsu.
お前まで倒し サスケはいったい
どこへ向かったのじゃ？
Where is Sasuke heading
that he'd resort to
hurting you as well?
おそらく 大蛇丸のところへ。
Most likely, to Orochimaru.
力を得るために。
To gain more power.
なんてことだ…。
What?
大蛇丸…。
Orochimaru...?
バカなことを。 そろそろ大蛇丸は→
That's so foolish!
Orochimaru will soon be looking
for his next vessel.
次なる器を欲する時期にきている。
自来也がそう言っていた。
サスケの身が危ない！
That's what Jiraiya said.
Sasuke is in danger!
《サクラ : そんな…》
No way!
サスケ君を大蛇丸に会わせてはダメだ。
We can't let Sasuke make contact
with Orochimaru.
それと 彼が里抜けしたことが
里内に広がるのは避けたい。
And...
I want to prevent any rumors
that he left the village from spreading.
至急 外出禁止令を
出そうと思います。
I'm going to issue
an urgent lockdown order.
うむ それがよかろう。
That's a good idea.
うちは一族の立場が これ以上
悪くならないためにも→
In order to prevent Uchiha's position
from worsening,
内々に そして速やかに
サスケ君を連れ戻さなければ。
we must handle this internally
and bring Sasuke back
quickly and smoothly.
NINJA ACADEMY
(ナルト)ハァ ハァ…。
いったい何だよ。
What's going on?
We're on lockdown,
but you called us to assemble...
外出禁止令が出てるのに
みんな集まれって。
(シカマル)話は 全員 揃ってからだ。
I'll explain once everyone is here.
ヘッ！ なに
もったいぶってんだってばよ。
Heh! What's with the attitude?
ん？ そういや
なんで教室に集合なんだ？
Oh, by the way, why are we meeting
in the classroom?
あ… ああ 他に思いつかなくてな。
U-Uh, I couldn't think
of anywhere else.
HOKAGE
へぇ～。
机とかイスって
こんなに小さかったっけ？
Were the desks and chairs
always this small?
(ヒナタ)ううん。
私たちが大きくなったの。
No, we just got bigger.
フッ そうだよな。
Guess you're right.
《サクラちゃん 目が イッちまってる。
Sakura's eyes are
popping out of her head...
こんなヤツのどこが
そんなにいいんだってばよ。
What's so great about
that guy anyways?
わからん》
I don't get it!
((テメエ ナルト！ サスケ君に
ガンたれてるんじゃないわよ！
Damn it, Naruto!
Don't glare at Sasuke!
どけ。
フン！
Move.
(いの)サスケ君 そんなヤツ
やっちゃいなよ！
Just beat him up, Sasuke!
そうよ そうよ！
That's right!
Huh? No way?!
Oops! Sorry!
(えっ!? ウソ！ あっ 悪ぃ！))
ん？
額当て…。
A headband...
(チョウジ)アカデミーの生徒は
まだ持てないよね。
A current Academy student wouldn't
have one of those yet.
(リー)すみません 遅くなりまして！
Sorry we're late!
(テンテン)もう！
アンタが逆立ちしながら来るから→
We're late because you insisted
on walking here on your hands.
遅れたんじゃない！
(ネジ)俺たちが最後か？
Are we the last ones?
ああ これで全員だ。
Yeah, we're all here now.
全員って サスケの野郎は？
All here?
What about that damn Sasuke?
そのサスケのことで面倒くせぇことが
起こっちまってな。
It's because of Sasuke that things
have become a bit of a drag.
なぁ サクラ。
(サクラ)う… うん。
Right, Sakura?
Uh... yeah!
私 病室の前でカカシ先生や
火影様の話を聞いちゃって…。
I was outside of
Lady Tsunade's office and
overheard Kakashi Sensei
and Lord Hokage talking...
サスケが 里抜けしたらしい。
Sasuke... left the village.
な… 何だって!?
(いの)サスケ君が!?
W-What?!
Sasuke did what?!
ど… どうして？
W-Why?
大蛇丸のもとに向かったそうだ。
He went to find Orochimaru.
よくわかんねえが 力を得るために
出ていっちまったらしい。
I don't know why, but he left
in order to get power.
(キバ)おい 大蛇丸って あの
伝説の三忍の１人じゃねえかよ。
Say... Isn't Orochimaru one
of the Legendary Sannin?!
(シノ)ああ しかも 里の人間を
何人も人体実験で殺し→
Yeah... Furthermore, the rumor is
that he killed several villagers
for his experiments and ran away
when he was discovered.
それがバレて 里を逃げ出した
という噂が。
そんなヤツのところへ…。
Why would he go to
someone like that?
今でさえ 危ない存在だってのに
どんな力をもらおうっていうのよ。
That man is still dangerous,
so what kind of power
is Sasuke seeking?
ナルト君…。
Naruto...
この額当て…。
This headband...
サスケのヤツ ここに来ていた。
Sasuke... was here.
木ノ葉の象徴である額当てを…。
The headband, which symbolizes
the Hidden Leaf...
しかも 俺たちの思い出の場所
アカデミーの教室に置いていった。
He left it here in
the Academy classroom,
which holds so many memories
for all of us.
つまり サスケは 俺たちを
木ノ葉を捨てたということか。
So in other words,
does it mean that Sasuke...
has abandoned us,
and the Hidden Leaf?
…んなわけねえよ！
No way!
確かに アイツは
ここんとこ ずっとイライラしてて→
Okay, so he's been a little irritable lately
and short with me,
俺に ガンたれてくるし
嫌なこと言うし→
and he said some sarcastic things
that made me mad...
俺だって ホント ムカついて
何なんだよって思って…。
だけどよ アイツは 木ノ葉の
俺たちの仲間だ！
But he's a Hidden Leaf...
he's our friend!
ナルト…。
Naruto...
大蛇丸は サスケ君の体を
器として乗っ取ろうとしてるの。
Orochimaru is going to
steal Sasuke's body
to use as his vessel...
サスケ君は そのことを知らない。
Sasuke doesn't know that.
サスケのヤツ… 何やってやがんだ。
What the hell is Sasuke doing?!
サスケを連れ戻すってばよ！
I'm gonna bring Sasuke back...
大蛇丸に会う前に 木ノ葉の里へ！
before he meets up with Orochimaru!
I'm bringing him back
to the village!
まあ 待てよ
今 うちはの立場は→
Hold on a minute.
We have to think of the position
the Uchiha are in too...
面倒くせぇことになってっからよ。
あまり 大事にはしたくねえ。
とはいえ ナルト１人だけに→
We can't make
a big deal out of this...
Still, we can't let Naruto go alone.
行かすわけには いかねえからな。
俺とナルトで行く。
So Naruto and I'll go.
ナルト！
Naruto!
ああ わかってるってばよ
サクラちゃん。
I know, Sakura.
I'll bring him back even if I have
to beat the hell outta him!
ぶん殴ってでも サスケのヤツを
連れて帰ってくるからよ。
(キバ)ヘヘッ 見ろよ。
ここが俺たちの秘密のトンネルだ。
See? This is our secret tunnel.
たまに赤丸と
月夜のピクニックと しゃれこんで→
Akamaru and I occasionally
go outside of the village
里の外へ出かけるんだ。
for fancy moonlight picnics.
(いの)何がピクニックよ。
ただの散歩じゃない。
Why are you calling it a picnic?
You just take him for walks!
そうよ いつか捕まるわよ！
Yeah! You're gonna get
caught one day!
そんなヘマするわけねえ。
I wouldn't mess up like that.
それに今は こいつのおかげで→
Besides, thanks to him,
we can go outside now,
向こう側 行けんだから
感謝してほしいな。
so you should be thankful.
シカマル そろそろ急がねえと。
ああ。
Shikamaru, we'd better hurry.
Yeah...
(サクラ)ナルト！
Naruto!
サクラちゃん！
Sakura?
ナルト お願い。
Naruto, please...
サスケ君を… サスケ君を
必ず連れ戻してきて！
Please bring Sasuke back,
no matter what!
大丈夫だって！
Don't worry!
サスケは ぜってぇ
俺が連れて帰る。
I'll bring Sasuke back.
約束するってばよ。
I promise you that!
頼んだぞ ナルト シカマル。
We're counting on you,
Naruto and Shikamaru.
ああ 任せろ！
Yeah, you bet!
《ナルト君… 気をつけて》
Naruto... Please be careful.
ん？
サスケのヤツ 大門から
堂々と出ていくだけあって→
Sasuke boldly walked
out the front gate
痕跡だらけだぜ。
おかげで追跡もしやすいがな。
leaving clear tracks everywhere.
That makes it easier to follow him.
《サスケ なんで…
なんでだってばよ》
Sasuke... Why?
Why did you—?
《俺は…》
I'm...
((フガク : はぁ～ やはり
イタチのときのようにはいかんか。
Why did I think you would
be like Itachi?
お前には
まだ早すぎたのかもしれんな。
Perhaps it's still too soon for you.
(イタチは同じ年頃には
完璧にできていたぞ))
Itachi was able to perfectly master it
when he was about your age.
《チクショウ！》
Damn it...
((千鳥流し！
Chidori Stream!
(ハァッ ハァッ ハァッ…))
《あの３年間を…》
Those three years...
((何だ この感じは…))
What is this feeling?
《あの３年間を
一瞬で終わらせてたまるか！》
I can't let those three years end
in a blink of an eye!
((ダンゾウ : うずまきナルト…。
Naruto Uzumaki...
(この３年で ずいぶん
力をつけたようだ))
He's gained a lot of strength
in three years.
《あの落ちこぼれが…。
That loser!
どんなことをしてでも
力を手に入れてやる！》
I'm going to obtain power,
no matter what it takes...
ミナト！
クシナ…。
Minato!
Kushina!
Listen to this...
(クシナ)ねぇ 聞いてよ。
外出禁止令が出てるのに→
Despite the lockdown order,
Naruto's snuck out and
gone off somewhere
ナルトったら
いつの間にか家出ちゃって→
and hasn't come back.
まだ帰ってないのよ。
Well uh... You're not supposed
to leave the house either.
いや キミも出てきちゃ
いけないんだけど…。
It's not only Naruto, ya know.
ナルトだけじゃないってばね。
Shikamaru's missing too.
シカマル君もいないらしくて。
え？
What?
Sakura and Ino were at home,
but something didn't seem right.
サクラちゃんや いのちゃんは
家にいたんだけど→
様子がおかしかったってばね。
It's like they were hiding something.
何か隠してるような…。
Hiding?
隠している？
うん。
Yeah.
Like what if they saw examples of
Naruto becoming a delinquent,
例えば ナルトが不良になってて→
like him going out every night,
doing something dangerous...?
夜な夜な いけない遊びに
出歩いてるのを→
And because Sakura and Ino
are just too nice,
サクラちゃんも いのちゃんも
優しいから→
they didn't tell us because
they don't want us to worry...
私たちに心配をかけまいと…。
って 聞いてるの？ ミナト！
あ あぁ…。
Are you even listening, Minato?!
Oh, yes.
ナルトなら大丈夫だよ。
Don't worry about Naruto.
I think he's probably out
doing some training.
おおかた どこかで修業でも
してるんだと思うよ。
This way!
こっちだ！
おう！
Right!
If Sasuke of the Uchiha Clan
leaves the village,
((うちはのサスケが里を出れば→
there will be a few who
will not stand idly by...
黙っておられぬ者どもが
出てくるだろう。
Mainly the children reared
by this cowardly system
三代目から 四代目へ継承された
腑抜けた体制の申し子たちがな。
that has been passed on by
the Third Hokage through to the Fourth.
ヤツらにつけ 動けば追え。
Keep watch on them,
and if they make a move,
follow them.
I want the gift to Orochimaru
to reach him safely.
大蛇丸への
進物を無事届けねばならない。
If they interfere, get rid of them.
邪魔なら 排除しろ。
どんな手段を使ってもいい。
Use whatever means necessary.
It's possible those fools won't be
the only ones on the move.
あるいは 動くのは
腑抜けだけとはかぎらぬ。
Therefore, I have gathered you,
the best of the Foundation.
ゆえに 根の者きっての
お前たちを こうして集めた。
(存分に励めよ))
Do your best.
Not good!
やばい！
Damn it!
クソッ！ しまっ…。
No...!
What?!
なに？
ゲジマユ！
Bushy Brows?!
ネジ テンテン。
Neji! Tenten!
What are you doing here?
どうして ここへ？
We saw some shadowy figures
pursuing you
２人が里を出てすぐ
追いかけていく影を見た。
as soon as you left the village.
で 急遽 俺たちが
助っ人に来たというわけだ。
And we hurried over to
be your back up.
I must say, being of help
like this
やっぱり 留守番してるよりも→
is much more invigorating than
just staying in the village!
こうやって皆さんの
お役に立てるほうが燃えますね！
Don't get too enthusiastic!
あまり 張り切り過ぎないでよ。
Nothing good happens
when you get too excited!
アンタが張り切ると
ロクなことないんだから。
No, get as enthusiastic
as you want.
いや 張り切ってもらうぜ
助かった。
You're a big help!
Incoming!
来る!!
You guys are—!
お前たちは…。
Those masks...!
その仮面… 暗部か？
They're ANBU?
って もう父ちゃんに
バレちまったのか。
Don't tell me Dad already
found out?!
Only the four here...
followed us.
追ってきたのは
この４人だけだ。
And there are five of us.
This will be easy!
僕たちは ５人です。
なんてこと ありませんよ！
はっ！ てやっ！
Sorry, but...
悪いがよ 父ちゃんの言いつけでも
引き下がれねえんだってばよ。
We can't retreat even if
Dad tells us to!
You idiots!
バカ！ お前たち 暗部相手に
何 まともに突っ込んでんだよ。
You can't just get into
a fight with the ANBU!
大蛇丸と会う前に→
We definitely have
to bring Sasuke back
before he meets up
with Orochimaru, ya know!
サスケを連れ戻さなきゃ
ならねえんだってばよ！
So please!
だから… 邪魔しないでくれ！
Don't get in our way!
ハーッ!!
くっ…。
Get back, everyone!
みんな 下がれ！
They're not ordinary ANBU...
《コイツら ただの暗部じゃねえな》
Naruto! Are you okay?
ナルト 大丈夫か？
They're coming at us
with intent to kill.
《本気で 殺しに来てやがる。
This is way too harsh...
いくらなんでも
外出禁止令を破ったくらいで→
considering that all we did was
disobey the lockdown order.
やりすぎだろう。
On top of that,
そのうえ 火影の息子 ナルトまで
殺しにかかるなんて→
there's no way they would try to
kill Naruto, the Hokage's son.
ありえねえ！》
I get it now...
そうか コイツら
火影直属の暗部じゃねえ。
These ANBU aren't the ones
under the Hokage.
They're with the militant faction
led by someone else.
三代目 四代目火影の
穏健派と違い→
Not the pacifist faction headed up
by the Third and Fourth Hokage.
武闘派の主任が
束ねていたという組織。
It was supposed to have been
dismantled already.
(シカマル)
今は 解散しているはずだが…。
I heard about it a while ago...
昔 聞いたことがある。
That a separate ANBU unit
still exists
暗部の中に 別動部隊として
暗部養成部門が存在していたと。
which serves as
a training division.
I remember it was called...
the Foundation.
たしか 根の者と言っていた。
The Foundation?
根？
《コイツらが 根の者!?》
So they belong to the Foundation...
《クソッ このままじゃ
サスケに追いつけねえ！》
Damn it! At this rate,
we'll never catch up to Sasuke!
sonna kimi o nazeka
I don't know why but someone like me
konna boku wa zutto hitei dekinakute
just couldn't reject someone like you
hashitteiru sono senaka o
So I kept running after you
taiyou mitai ni oikaketa
like you were the sun
te ga todokisou na yume wa kachi ga nainda
A dream that's within reach doesn't have any value
zettai ni muri datte iwareru kurai ga ii
I like it better when I'm told it's unreachable
akirameru nante itsudatte dekiru kara
I can give up any time I want
hikihanasaretemo boku wa ganbarou
so I'll keep trying no matter how much we're pulled apart
hito wa doushite ase nagashite kisoiau no ka?
Why do people sweat and fight so hard?
jibun no sonzai o shoumei shitai
I want to prove that I exist
sonna kimi wa kitto
That someone like you has a fear
konna boku niwa nai kodoku ni obieterunda
of being alone that someone like me doesn't have
sono saki niwa daremo inai
There's no one beyond that point
ushiro ni chikadzuku fuan dake
As anxiety closes in from behind
boku ga iru
I will be there
These guys aren't
under the Hokage!
＜今 人気絶頂の三山ひろしさんと
山内惠介さんが→
They're from the underground
organization, the Foundation.
I don't care if they're underground
or aboveground!
はるな愛さん 水谷千重子さんと
ペアを組んで突撃取材＞
If you're trying to kill me,
come at me and fair and square
with your faces showing!
Just try and get me!
Such a hot-blooded child...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Pursuers"
We're from the same village,
but these guys...
What's going on?